ENOBONG ENOBONG

WRITER, RESEARCHER & EDITOR

3 JOHN SOARES CLOSE, LAGOS, LAGOS 105101 | +2348055075727 | enobongenobong01@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/enobong-enobong-618002265

Professional Summary

Proficient and versatile writer (academic, legal, content, and creative writing), researcher, and editor with 6+ years of experience. Explores a broad spectrum of writing niches. Widely published locally and internationally in literary magazines (print and electronic).

Skills

- Editing
- Proofreading
- Copyediting
- Academic writing
- Legal writing
- Content writing
- Copywriting
- Digital content marketing
- Proposal writing

- Grant writing
- Creative writing
- Research
- Legal research
- Data analysis
- **SEO**
- Experiential knowledge of several referencing/citation styles—APA, MLA, OSCOLA, Chicago, Harvard, Bluebook, and MHRA

Work Experience

Editor and Proofreader

PaperTrue

07/2023 - Present

1. Proofread manuscripts:

- - a. Remove language errors, mechanical errors, and inconsistencies in the manuscript (including errors in the spelling, grammar, typography, punctuation, etc.).
 - b. Remove deviations from the given style sheet, referencing style, and formatting requirements.
- 2. Copy-edit manuscripts:
 - a. Improve the sentence structure, clarity, smoothness, coherence, cohesion, flow, and consistency of the writing, through carrying out line-by-line editing.
 - b. Check for correctness in the usage, syntax, and other mechanics of style.
 - c. Ensure the author's original meaning and voice are retained in the edited manuscript.

Singapore (Remote)

- d. Ensure consistent adherence to the given formatting requirements, as well as referencing requirements.
- 3. Critique manuscripts:
 - a. Provide the author of the manuscript with critical, constructive, and courteous feedback regarding the form as well as the content of their writing, through making comments using MS Word's comment feature.
 - b. Point out internal discrepancies and lacunae, if any, in the manuscript's content (including facts, arguments, opinions, ideas, etc.).
 - c. Point out overall structural or organizational problems, if any, in the manuscript's content.
- 4. Abide by professional standards and world best practices governing the editing ecosystem.

Associate Writer and Researcher

Ori David Consult Writers' Lounge

12/2020 - Present

Lagos, Nigeria

 Researcher and writer of research proposals, research papers, academic papers, dissertations, theses, projects and other long-form essays on several fields, prominently the legal, corporate, industrial, maritime, health, educational, economics, arts, humanities, psychology, socioeconomic, and socio-political landscapes.

Head Writer

SaintlyCreative Writing Consult

11/2017 - 08/2022

Lagos, Nigeria

- Handled the first set of jobs—blog writing, web content writing, copywriting, academic
 writing, book reviews, research, proofreading and editing—that helped pull massive
 patronage to the business in the first few weeks of its establishment.
- Captained the consult into being a household name and built an excellent reputation for it through timely and consistent delivery of excellently executed projects and warm firm-toclient relationship.

Education

Bachelor of Laws (LLB), Class of 2024

University of Lagos – Akoka, Lagos, Nigeria

Accomplishments

- Best of the Net Nominee, Arts Lounge Magazine (2021)
- Runner-up, Torchbearers Impact Network Write-up Contest (2021)

Top-50-Best Memorialist, Nelson Mandela World Human Rights Moot Court Competition

(2022)